<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<data>
	<item name="Dan Herron" position="Creative Director" image="dan.jpg">Dan is an award-winning still and video advertising photographer, film editor, and graphic designer based in Austin, Texas, with more than 15 years experience as corporate photographer and marketing leader for GE Energy, KVUE-TV-ABC Television News, IBM, Golfsmith, Capital Metro, and the Intermark Group, Strong Advertising Agency.
Raised in Marble Falls, the heart of the Texas Hill Country (Luckenbach, Texas on the weekends), Dan creates exceptional creative marketing collateral and photography for advertising, corporate, editorial, and individual clients.
Though he specializes in photographing projects on location, he is quite proficient at shooting people and products in the studio environment as well. His wide range of experience also incorporates shooting architecture and various commercial facilities as well as video production, motion graphics, and editing.
Dan has a BA Degree in mass communication from the University of Central Oklahoma and a MS degree in management from Southern Nazarene University. Dan is a member of the prestigious, American Society of Media Photographers (ASMP) and National Association of Photoshop Professionals (NAPP).
	</item>
	
	<item name="Michael Pugliese" position="Director of Photography" image="mike.jpg">Michael provides a forward thinking approach to content creation from the perspective of unique lens', mediums & techniques; Tailor made solutions for commercial work, head shots, event coverage, advertising, and a whole lot more.  His scientific approach to imaging and in-depth technical knowledge has made him one of Austin's brightest up-and-coming DPs.  In addition to being published in various magazines, catalogs and scientific journals across the nation, he has had the honor of photographing some of the biggest superstars in the electronic music scene.  He frequently works on documenting speleological scientific expeditionary work in Mexico, where he captures the inner realms of the Earth on film.</item>
	<item name="Jack Frink" position="Producer/Writer/Director" image="jack.jpg">Jack was born in Austin, Texas on August 5th, 1985. From a young age he showed an interest in film and music, and has followed those hobbies for the entirety of his adult life. Frink produced, wrote and directed Superhero: A Crime Story, his first feature-length film, in 2006. In 2008 he graduated with a Bachelor’s Degree in Radio-Television-Film from the University of Texas. During his studies he completed various film projects, both as creator and collaborator. 	Since graduating he has moved into the professional sector, working in various guises as assistant director, production assistant, writer, director, producer, etc. for both independent feature shoots and select PSAs. He has started work on his second major screenplay but has no plans for production until proper funding can be found.	Frink is a producer, writer and director by trade, but he also has been playing guitar since he was 11 years old. He plays for and manages the alternative rock group Little Triggers. He loves UT sports and roots for the San Antonio Spurs.</item>
	<item name="Ben Rubin" position="Web/Graphic Designer" image="ben.jpg">Michael provides a forward thinking approach to content creation from the perspective of unique lens', mediums & techniques; Tailor made solutions for commercial work, head shots, event coverage, advertising, and a whole lot more.  His scientific approach to imaging and in-depth technical knowledge has made him one of Austin's brightest up-and-coming DPs.  In addition to being published in various magazines, catalogs and scientific journals across the nation, he has had the honor of photographing some of the biggest superstars in the electronic music scene.  He frequently works on documenting speleological scientific expeditionary work in Mexico, where he captures the inner realms of the Earth on film.</item>
</data>